We wanted also to go through a thorough physical exam and I'm going to ask the owner of this kitty cat that if they have any health concerns.
So, that's where we're going to start.
We want to go ahead and have a good look at your cat.
I think I actually put your kitty cat to sleep by putting him in there and talking so quietly.
But, what we're going to do is bring the kitty cat out and have a little bit of an exam.
Now, do you have any particular concerns about your cat's health?
As you mentioned, the upper respiratory would be my main concern.
Have you seen any problems with that?
Have you seen your kitty cat do any sneezing or watering from the eyes or anything?
No. Ok. Well, we're going to go through just a few things while we look at your kitty cat. It's very important I think, at this age to try and do some little training with your cat and let it be used to being handled.
And, with a little bit of luck you'll learn how to brush their teeth.
Take care of their nails and things like that.
But, we're going to do a thorough physical exam now and look your kitty cat all over.
Unfortunately, your cat now is so small it doesn't even move our scales.
So, that means she's lighter I'm sorry he's lighter than three pounds. So, it's just kind of a small kitty. Probably next time, in about a month when you come in we'll be able to get a more accurate weight.
So, we start looking at their eyes first and everything is clear in the eyes.
We would like to look in the ear and the eyes and be sure there isn't any ear mites.
Cats frequently get some ear mites.
And, they're perfectly clear.
I'm not seeing any problems there.
And, again this is all part of the stuff that might be good for you to do at home is to hold onto the ear and touch the kitty cat all over.
And, it makes it less traumatic when we have to have a look at them during the exam.
We like to be sure that their eyes are clear.
And, there is just a little bit of discharge coming from this cat's eye.
You can see right in the corner here.
And, so one of those things that you're going to want to watch for is to be sure you don't get a lot of discharge from this cat's eye or any sneezing.
If that happens, you should give me a call.
Now, these are all baby teeth.
You can see that we don't have any adult teeth yet, because we're so young.
And, we open it up and look all the way down in there.
They kind of think that's kind of a mean thing to do at first.
But, they get used to it.
And, everything looks normal.
Now, all of those teeth that you see there are going to fall out.
We get a whole new set of teeth and those are all baby teeth.
And, by the time your cat is six months of age there won't be any baby teeth left only adult teeth.
So, we're going to listen to the heart.
And, kitty's purring a lot.
So, it's hard to hear the heart.
There we go.
And, the lungs are fine.
Everything is clear.
And, you just want to play don't you?
You want to go ahead and look at the underside too and be sure that there's no particular problems with your cat.
There's no hernia and both of the testicles have come down.
So, we're in great shape.